# CARYN HAMILTON, MPH

### PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Mobile: (978) 578-1722

Email: caryn.hamilton1221@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Motivated and dedicated public health professional focused on healthcare project management. Extensive experience in public health services, program/project management, and healthcare consulting within new startup healthcare companies. Recent work has been involved in project management support for value based care organizations in the CKD & ESKD space.

## **SKILLS:**

Vendor Management & 3<sup>rd</sup> Party Integration Experience

Collaborative talent + problem solving skills

Budget management & analysis

Microsoft Office/ Google Suite

Leadership Experience in cross functional teams & markets

Project Management Sites (Jira Service Management, Monday.com, Confluence, Asana, Slack, Zoom, G Suite)

Project Management Methodologies (Scrum, Agile, Waterfall)

Quality Improvement/Quality Assurance Measurement Experience

Value Based Care Healthcare/Tech Startup Experience

Population Health- Program Management/B2B Marketing Experience (Salesforce)

### **WORK HISTORY:**

### JULY 2024 - Present: Project Manager- Interwell Health - Remote in Boston, MA

- Develop comprehensive project plans for kidney care initiatives under the VBC model, detailing project goals, timelines, resources, budget, and key milestones.
- Collaborate with clinical teams, data analysts, IT, and other stakeholders to ensure alignment with organizational goals and patient care objectives.
- Serve as the primary point of contact for all project-related communications between internal teams, external partners, and vendors.
- Proactively identify project risks and issues that could impact project timelines, budget, or quality of care.
- Stay informed on regulatory changes affecting VBC in kidney care and adjust projects to meet new requirements.
- Oversee the integration of third-party tools and platforms that may be required to support the projects, such as data analytics systems or care management software.

# MAY 2023- JULY 2024: Psychiatry & Behavioral Health Project Manager- Atrius Health- Newton, MA

- Worked closely with service-line leaders to implement solutions and support the development of systems prioritizing both sustainability and continuous improvement.
- Managed implementation of innovation projects at various stages of maturity and a range of sizes and scope that are critical to support and achieve key organizational goals of Atrius Health
- Managed relationships with key stakeholders internal to and external to Atrius Health, as needed for a given innovation project, in service of project implementation and ongoing success.
- During pilot phase, leads research, design, and testing of the solution at scale in a real-world setting, in collaboration with the project team and relevant stakeholders.
- Provided monitoring analysis as to on-going implementation and acceptance as needed.

 Facilitated change management as needed to introduce and spread new innovations within the organization.

# JUNE 2022- DECEMBER 2022: Growth Operations Associate Project Manager - New Markets- Eleanor Health Inc- Boston, MA

- Conducted key market research and stakeholder analysis to inform senior leadership on key locations in various states for new market launches.
- Customer Success Skills -effective collaboration with cross functional teams and key stakeholders to improve business needs and clinical care.
- Successful development and rollout of multiple company-wide SOPs to improve employee transitions within the organization.
- Led weekly new clinic launch meetings to oversee and manage all clinic operation startup tasks and dependencies from start to finish.
- Project managed all company phases of market launch process of expanding our clinic footprint within the organization.
- Extensive collaboration on all population health engagement processes within the organization. Providing key research and engagement metrics for presentation to senior leadership.
- Defining and driving key quality engagement projects within the organization to drive member involvement and improving overall member retention rates.
- Utilized industry standards and best practices for project management and participated in the development and implementation of new or improved project management processes.
- Worked closely with internal stakeholders and external clients to establish, communicate, and manage project timelines, objectives, milestones, and deliverables.
- Close partnership with our VP of operational excellence and Chief Business Officer to present strategic growth projects & provide insight on organizational project updates + strategic planning.
- Recent population health project management driving member engagement rates and decreasing overall retention rates with clinical services.

# MARCH 2020- JUNE 2022: Neonatal Intensive Care Unit-Project Manager- Tufts Children's Hospital- Boston, MA

- Manage, enter & analyze data for over 1,000 premature and acutely ill infants; providing evidence to inform changes in hospital stay and care.
- Involved in quality improvement initiatives to improve overall health of premature infants, finding research and literature reviews of neonatal concerns.
- Developed research/overall quality improvement projects on the hospitals standard of care, decreasing morbidity rates in infants.
- Run and distribute project specific metric reports
- Grant research & grant writing to secure funds for the hospitals NICU
- Coordination of projects, set agendas, and delegation of project tasks in the NICU.
- Project management and advising on several neonatal quality improvement projects & research projects.
- Promotion of project goals and timelines in various clinical settings within the hospital.
- Implementation of new clinical software programs prior to Go-Live period
- Extensive project management with launching new clinical software programs (EPIC, Neodata, eClinicalWorks)
- Responsible for the various builds of EPIC electronic medical record system for various NICU related clinical research
- Responsible for various audit's conducted over the medical center to improve patient safety measures.

• Co-author listed on abstract: "Reducing Retinopathy of Prematurity by Minimizing Hyperoxia: A Multidisciplinary Quality Improvement Project". Submitted to AAP conference for publication.

### SEPTEMBER 2019- SEPTEMBER 2020- Intern: Greater Lowell Health Alliance- Lowell, MA

- Community health event collaboration
- Substance Use Prevention Education experience
- Program Coordination of health events and implementation of community outreach events.
- Mental Health task force meetings & Substance Abuse Coalition Team meetings
- Grant proposals & Application Review
- Community Outreach and Education for at risk populations.
- Extensive collaboration with Lowell General Hospital, Substance Use & Disorder Task Force, Mental Health Coalition, LGBTQ Subcommittee, Perinatal Mental Health, and Social Determinants Subcommittee
- Created infographics (based on the 2019 Community Health Needs Assessment) and took kits for community members to navigate various health related issues to sustain healthy lives.
- Member of the Grant Review Committee on behalf of the Greater Lowell Health Alliance, reviewing and scoring twenty-five proposals. Contributed to the decision making to distribute \$185,000 in funds.
- Experience working with diverse culture in Lowell, MA. Focusing on health diversity & promotion.

### **EDUCATION:**

Master's Degree: Public Health - Southern New Hampshire University

• Concentration: Healthcare Administration/ Health Care Management

Bachelor of Science: Public Health Degree: University of Massachusetts Lowell, MA

• Concentration: Health Sciences/Public Health

#### **CERTIFICATIONS:**

**CPR** Certified

**AED Certified** 

Monday.com User Certification- Project Management

### **VOLUNTEER SERVICE:**

- Strides Classroom (assistance and help with disabled students)
- Haven for Hunger
- Walk for Hospice
- Habitat for Humanity

**REFERENCES:** (Available upon request)